



Sérgio Barriviera Miguel

Nationality: Portuguese Date of birth: 10/09/1979

• Home: Estado da India, 660 Ap. 52, 4430-098 Porto (Portugal)

ABOUT ME

IT professional with 20+ years of hands-on experience in the field of software development. Active in the fields of architecture, design, requirements analysis, data modeling, prototyping, full-stack web, and mobile development. An eternal learner that really loves what he does.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CTO, Hands-On Software Architect (Remote)

Everup [29/04/2020 - Current]

City: London

Country: United Kingdom

Responsible for designing and implementing a cloud-native architecture for a prize-linked savings platform composed of gamified products such as cash accounts, debit cards, and gift cards shop.

Developing a hybrid mobile application using React Native and creating a serverless, microservice event-driven architecture hosted on AWS.

As part of my responsibilities, I successfully managed a remote distributed team consisting of developers, testers, and designers. I also took charge of engaging with third-party service providers, including agencies, banking services, and identity verification companies.

During this period, we achieved a significant milestone by obtaining approval from the Financial Conduct Authority (FCA). Through my contributions and leadership, I played a pivotal role in delivering a robust and scalable solution that met the company's objectives which gave the company the ability to get substantial investments, where two rounds of funding were obtained through crowdfunding, reflecting the trust and confidence of a broad community of investors in our innovative fintech platform. More information can be found at: https://www.crowdcube.com/companies/everup-ltd/pitches/lKnv7q?country=GB

Everup - Prize Linked App

https://www.everup.uk/ https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/everup/id1531616116 https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.everup

Blockchain Engineer (Remote)

Animoca Brands [30/10/2019 – 28/04/2020]

City: Pokfulam, Hong Kong

Country: China

Developing and maintaining smart contracts to manage digital game assets using industry-standard specifications such as ERC-20, ERC-721, and ERC-1155.

Utilized Solidity programming and frameworks like Truffle and Hardhat to implement and deploy smart contracts on Ethereum Blockchain.

Collaborated with security auditors to identify potential vulnerabilities and ensure the robustness of smart contract implementations.

CTO, Hands-On Software Architect (Remote)

SingularCK [16/06/2018 – 26/10/2019]

City: London

Country: United Kingdom

Responsible for creating a cloud-native architecture for a digital collectibles marketplace based on blockchain technology, using smart contracts to issue and manage digital assets (NFTs).

As part of my role at SingularCK, I managed a remote distributed team comprising developers, testers, and designers. Reporting directly to the CEO, I oversaw the entire product lifecycle, including product requirements, development, integration, quality control, and deployment. Additionally, I monitored technical resources and performance KPIs since the product activation.

Initially, I worked on-site for two months and later transitioned to a remote position.

NinjaStickers Digital Collectibles

https://www.ninjastickers.com/motogp/

Web application created with Java based on Stellar and Ethereum Blockchain and AWS cloud services

Due to the company's successful business, it was acquired by an Asian company (Animoca Brands) specializing in games and blockchain. More information can be found at: https://www.animocabrands.com/acquires-ninjastickers

Software Architect, Full-stack Developer and Mobile Developer (Remote)

Setia Tecnologia [31/10/2017 - 10/06/2018]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Responsible for the entire project lifecycle, such as payment gateways, internet banking, and billing systems, from inception to delivery, utilizing agile software development methodology able to support some of the CMMi requirements (Levels 2 and 3).

Main Projects

- Invoice and Billing Systems (Java, WebSphere, and Mainframe Integration)
- Payment Gateway (Mainframe JCA/CTG, SOAP, and REST Integration. Using ISO 8583 as Message Standard and IBM ConnectDirect to exchange data)
- Internet Banking (Java, ASP, WebSphere, Mainframe JCA/CTG, SOAP, and IBM MQ Integration)
- Designing and Implementing a Mobile Native Android Architecture considering resource optimization and offline scenarios
- Using Containers and Cloud Providers to create Cloud-Native applications: Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, and AWS (S3, EC2, ECS, ECR, CloudWatch, CloudTrail, Lambda, and other services)
- Software performance and optimization analysis reports
- RPA (Automation Anywhere)

Main Customers

Financial Institutions and Banking (Brazil)

Telco - Zeroasette (Italy)

Senior Software Engineer

Novabase [01/05/2017 - 21/03/2018]

City: Porto

Country: Portugal

Developing Customer Relationship Management Software Integrated with Telco/CTI Solutions.

Main Projects

Unified Front-end in Retail and Call Centres. UFE is designed over Celfocus Omnichannel, a telco-oriented solution designed and owned by Celfocus (JEE based on Oracle solutions). GDPR compliance application.

Main Customers

Telco - Vodafone (Ireland)

Software Architect, Full-stack Developer and Project Leader

Setia Tecnologia [14/12/2008 – 27/04/2017]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Dealing with full project life cycle development for high-performance desktop, web, and mobile applications. Applying Gamification to engage users and customers in order to connect smaller tasks to larger goals.

Main Projects

- E-commerce Platform Setia WebStore (White label platform, ASP.NET/C#)
- Electronic Payments (API Design and Backend Development Java/JEE/Spring)
- Payment Gateway (Mainframe JCA/CTG, SOAP, and REST Integration. Using ISO 8583 as Message Standard and IBM ConnectDirect to exchange data)
- Internet Banking (Mainframe JCA/CTG, SOAP, and IBM MQ Series Integration)
- Invoice and Billing Software
- Mobile Contactless Payment (NFC) and Wallet App Specification
- Monitoring, Data analysis, ETL, KPI Composition, and Web Reports
- Corporate WebSites with CMS Integration
- Risk Management System (Fraud Detection and Prevention: Rule-based system)
- Financial Simulation Tool (Insurance)
- RPA (Automation Anywhere)

Main Customers

Financial Institutions and Banking (Brazil and Italy)

Senior Software Engineer

Safra National Bank [02/08/2008 - 12/12/2008]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Caring for Online Stock Trading - Safra Home Broker

System Analyst and Software Development Team Leader

Compugraf Telecom [30/08/2001 – 31/07/2008]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Developing Customer Relationship Management Software Integrated with Telco/CTI Solutions. CRM and Telco Solutions for Companies like Carrefour, Citroen, Peugeot, Axial, Telefonica and Casas Bahia Working with Alcatel, Avaya and Aspect solutions. Integration with others CRMs like Sibel and Clarify

System Analyst

Sebrae [02/10/2000 - 27/08/2001]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Financial Products Simulation Tool (loans and investments)

Designer, WebDesigner and Developer

3D Brasil Advertising [02/03/1998 – 29/09/2000]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Creation of brands, logos, websites, and e-commerce platforms. Working with CGI, Perl, and ASP as the main technology stack.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering

Instituto de Pesquisas Tecnológicas - IPT (USP) [08/09/2012 - 08/07/2016]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Postgraduate Education, Software Engineering

Instituto Tecnológico de Aeronáutica - ITA [03/04/2008 - 06/08/2010]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Specialization, Project Management

Fundação Getulio Vargas - FGV [02/05/2006 - 01/08/2007]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

Bachelor's degree, Social Communication having specialized in Advertising and Publicity

Faculdades Oswaldo Cruz [31/01/1997 – 13/12/2001]

City: Sao Paulo Country: Brazil

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English Spanish

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2 LISTENING A2 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

20+ years of hands-on experience in the field of software development

Active in the fields of architecture, design, requirements analysis, data modeling, prototyping, and full-stack web and mobile development.

Certifications

- Oracle Certified Master, Java EE 5 Enterprise Architect (OCMJEA)
- Oracle Certified Master, Java EE 6 Enterprise Architect (OCMJEA)
- Oracle Certified Professional, Java EE 5 Business Component Developer
- Sun Certified Web Component Developer for the Java Platform, EE 5
- Sun Certified Programmer for the Java Platform, SE 6
- Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 5/SE 6

- Certified Scrum Master (CSM)
- IBM Certified Solution Designer
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Automation Anywhere Certified Advanced RPA Professional

Financial Skills

Payment Gateway, ISO 8583, Payment Service Directive (PSD), Payment Card Industry (PCI-DSS), and OpenBanking. During my last job we got the Financial Conduct Authority approval (FCA/FRN: 900573)

Gaming and Gambling Skills

Familiar with Game Design, Gamification, Gambling Rules, and Gambling Commission directives.

Technical Skills

Modeling: Domain-driven design (DDD), Clean Architecture, and Iconix.

<u>Java:</u> version 1.3 through Java 11, covering both Standard and Enterprise Edition, and proficiency in utilizing Oracle, Spring, and Apache frameworks. JSP, JSF, Spring MVC, WebFlux, Tiles, and Thymeleaf. *Whenever possible JHipster will be used.*

NodelS: version 8 through 18. Express, Mongoose, Passport, and others.

Javascript & Typescript: JQuery, AngularJS, React, Backbone, Underscore, and others.

Mobile: React Native, Cordova, and Ionic. Knowledgeable with native Android development.

<u>Application Servers:</u> WebSphere (5,6,7,8,8.5), JBoss (AS, Wildfly, EAP), and Weblogic. Tomcat and Underdown (SpringBoot).

Message Broker: IBM MQ Series, RabbitMQ, and AWS SQS.

Legacy: CORBA, IDL, Mainframe Integration (Custom Resource Adapters - JCA), Visual Basic 6.0, and C++.

<u>Cloud:</u> AWS and Heroku. Extensive experience with AWS (ECS, EC2, S3, SQS, SNS, Lambda, Step Functions, BeanStalk, Kinesis, DynamoDB, ReadShidft, Glue, and other services).

<u>Databases:</u> SQL Server (DBA Previous Experience), MySQL, Postgres, Db2, Oracle, DynamoDB, MongoDB, and Neo4i.

<u>Cache/In-memory:</u> Redis and Memcached.

<u>Security:</u> Experienced with Web Application Firewalls (AWS WAF, Shield, and F5). Familiar with OWASP security guidelines.

Container and Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes, and AWS ECS/ECR.

Blockchain: Smart contract development using Solidity and frameworks like Truffle and Hardhat.

<u>Machine Learning:</u> Python, Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook. Familiar with Hadoop and Spark and currently studying SageMaker and Large Language Models (LLM).

<u>Automation:</u> RPA (Automation Anywhere) and Shell Scripts.

Tools

Analysis: Enterprise Architect and Visual Paradigm

Dev-IDE: Eclipse, IntelliJ, and VSCode.

Test-Tools: Selenium, Meter and SoapUI

CI & CD Tools: Jenkins, Maven, Ant, Grunt. Bitrise for mobile application.

Libs management: Nexus

QA-Tools: PMD, Checkstyle, Firebug, SonarCube, and SonarLint